Judgement is coming.
Dredd is a action, science fiction film directed by Pete Travis.
In the future, America is a dystopian wasteland.
The latest scourge is Ma-Ma, a prostitute-turned-drug pusher with a
dangerous new drug and aims to take over the city.
The only possibility of stopping her is an elite group of urban police called Judges, who combine
the duties of judge, jury and executioner to deliver a brutal brand of swift justice.
But even the top-ranking Judge, Dredd, discovers that taking down Ma-Ma isn’t as easy as
it seems in this explosive adaptation of the hugely popular comic series.
Judge Dredd, played by Karl Urban.
Cassandra Anderson, played by Olivia Thirlby.
Ma-Ma, played by Lena Headey.
Kay, played by Wood Harris.
Judge Lex, played by Langley Kirkwood.
Ma-Ma Bodyguard, played by Tamer Burjaq.
Dredd is a 2012 science fiction and action film directed by Pete
Travis and written and produced by Alex Garland.
It is based on the 2000 AD comic strip Judge Dredd and its eponymous
character created by John Wagner and Carlos Ezquerra.
Karl Urban stars as Judge Dredd, a law enforcer given the power of judge, jury, and executioner in a
vast, dystopic metropolis called Mega-City One that lies in a post-apocalyptic wasteland.
Dredd and his rookie partner, Judge Anderson (Olivia Thirlby), are forced to bring order to a 200-storey
high-rise block of apartments and deal with its resident drug lord, Ma-Ma (Lena Headey).
Garland began writing the script in 2006, although the development of a new Judge Dredd film
adaptation, unrelated to the 1995 film Judge Dredd, was not announced until December 2008.
Produced by British studio DNA Films, Dredd began principal
photography, using 3D cameras throughout, in November 2010.
Filming took place on practical sets and
locations in Cape Town and Johannesburg.
Dredd was released on 7 September 2012 in the United
Kingdom and on 21 September worldwide.
Critics were generally positive about the film's visual effects, casting and action sequences, while criticism focused on
excessive violence as well as a perceived lack of the satirical elements that are found in the source comic.
Despite the positive critical response, the film earned just over $41 million
at the box office on an estimated budget of $30–45 million.
The theatrical gross made a sequel unlikely, but home media sales and fan efforts endorsed by 2000
AD's publisher Rebellion Developments have maintained the possibility of a second film.
The film explores themes of metropolis, corruption, police, judge, gangster.
The tone is dark and thought_provoking.